Adult Education Audio and Video Collection
Adult Education Audio and Video Collection
- Audiocassettes
  - 8169-01/02 Humanizing Adult Education Research. Ronald Hilton, Ph.D. Interviews Ann Koch, 4/12/79 (Box 18)
  - 8170-01 Humanizing Adult Education. Ronald Hilton, Ph.D. Interviews Dr. Bob Buerschaper, 10/30/79 (Box 18)
  - 8171-01 Humanizing Adult Education Research. Ronald Hilton, Ph.D. Interviews Margaret Sovie, 6/3/75 (Box 18)
  - 8172-01 Humanizing Adult Education Research. Ronald Hilton, Ph.D. Interviews Bonaro Overstreet, 11/80 (Box 18)
  - 8173-01 Humanizing Adult Education Research, Ronald Hilton, Ph.D. Interviews Herbert Hunsaker, 11/8/79 (Box 18)
  - 8183-01 Boshler/Knox Panel. AEA, 1978 (Box 18)
  - 8184-01 Glimpses of the Past: CAAE 1935-1975. (Box 18)
  - 8185-01 South Africa, Reverend Abraham Hector, Capetown, SA, 9/6/81 (Box 18)
  - 8186-01 Memorial Service James R. Kidd, 3/24/82 (Box 18)
  - 8900-01 / C-199 Backgrounds of Central Europe, Dr. Thomas Kozma, Dec 11, 1989; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
    Gift of Alex Charters, 2016.
  - 8901-01, 8901-02 / C-193, C-194 NUCEA Oral History Project, Interview of Alex Charters, Dec 1988; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
  - 8902-01 / C-200 Reflections by Alex Charters on adult and continuing education, 1/31/90; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
  - 8903-01 / C-162 Dr. Per Himmelstrup Metro. Syr. Comm., 2/16/88; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
  - 8904-01 / C-192 Dusan Savicevic interviewed by Peg Bonesteel, Oct 28, 1988; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
  - 8905-01m 8905-02, 8905-03 / C-195, C-196, C-197 Albert Mgulambwa History of African nations as context for adult ed. programs, undated; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
  - 8906-01a, 8906-01b / C-160, C-161 Interview of Alex Charters by Lydia Lavin, CSLEA, Jan 1988; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
  - 8907-01 / C-198 Alex Charters Experiences in radio and television, Dec 1989; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
  - 8908-01 / C-164 Dr Sei Mura [Seiichi Okamura] Adult ed. in Japan, Oct 12, 1988; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
  - 8909-01 / C-163 Harold Stubblefield CSLEA and related matters, 3/2/88; 1/4 inch audiocassette (Box 22)
- Videotapes (VT), All VT tapes transferred to University Archives, as part of the SU SYNAPSE Collection.
  - 1980 School of Education Colloquia: Toward a Learning Society: Government Policy and the Education of Adults. William M. Rivera, Convener.
    - VT 170, VT 171 The Politics of Funding for Education of Adults, Mr. Charles Lee, Executive Director of the Committee for Full Funding, Washington, DC., 9 Oct 1980; 2 tapes
    - VT 172, VT 173 Financing the Learning Society, Dr. Norman Kurland, Executive Director of Adult Learning Service, SED, Albany, NY 12234., 13 Nov 1980; 2 tapes
    - VT 174 Government Support for the Education of Adults in the Humanities, Dr. Leonard P. Oliver, Special Assistant to the Chairman, National Endowment of the Humanities, Washington, DC., 16 Oct 1980
    - VT 175 Policy Developments and the Lobbying Process for the Education of Adults, Ms. Miriam Kazanjian, Federal Relations Representative, NYS Education Dept. offices, Washington, DC., 30 Oct 1980
  - 1981 School of Education Colloquia: Taking Sides in the Learning Society: Controversial Issues in Education for Adu1ts, William M. Rivera, Convener.
    - VT 176, VT 177, VT 178 Conflict of Partnership: A Comprehensive Policy of Education for Adults. William M. Rivera, Convener. January 29, 1981: Conflict of Partnership: A Comprehensive Policy of Education for Adults, Mr. William J. Hilton, Director of Lifelong Learning Project, Education Commission of the States, Denver, CO., 29 Jan 1981; 3 tapes
    - VT 179, VT 180, VT 181 Lifelong Learning's 'Bill of Rights' - Does the state Owe All Adults an Education? Mr. Garrett W. Murphy, Director of the Division of Continuing Education, Albany, NY., 19 Feb 1981; 3 tapes
    - VT 182, VT 183 Advice and Consent: Influencing Federal Policy in Continuing Education, Dr. William G. Shannon, Executive Director, National Advisory Council for Continuing Education, Washington, DC., 19 Mar 1981; 3 tapes
    - VT 184, VT 185, VT 186 What Would Constitute a Fully Human Policy for Adults? Mr. Warren L. Ziegler, Futures Invention Associates, Denver, CO., 2 Apr 1981; 3 tapes
  - 1981 Clearinghouse of Resources for Educators of Adults in Conjunction with the Center for Human Development Open Seminar. William M. Rivera, Convener.
    - VT 187, VT 188, VT 189 Policy and Research Needs in Education for Disabled Adults, Mr. William Langner, Office of Adult Learning and Community School Relations U.S. Department of Education., 25 Feb 1981; 3 tapes
- Videocassettes (VC)
  - Mentors Series (University of Georgia: Athens, GA), 1974
    - VC 1008 New dimensions in living, 1 tape U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 18)
    - VC 1009 The Beginnings. Interviews with Hallenbeck, Hunsaker, McClusky, Spence, Henrickson, Houle, Essert., 1 tape U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 18)
    - VC 1010 Early leaders in university adult education. An interview with Paul Essert., 1 tape U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1011 Interviews with Hendrickson and McClusky., 1 tape U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1012 Interviews with Houle, Hunsaker, Sheats., 1 tape U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
  - Mentors II Series (University of Georgia: Athens, GA), 1985
    - VC 1073 Curtis Ulmer, 1 tape, 31 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1074 Phyllis Cunningham, Malcolm Knowles, William Griffith., 1 tape, 29 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1075 Phyllis Cunningham., 1 tape U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1076 Malcolm Knowles., 1 tape, 29 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1077 William Griffith., 1 tape, 30 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1078 Alex Charters, Curtis Ulmer, Alan Knox., 1 tape, 30 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1079 George Aker, Cyril O. Houle, Burton Kreitlow., 1 tape, 30 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1080 Eugene Johnson., 1 tape, 30 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1081 Cyril O. Houle., 1 tape, 32 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1082 George Aker., 1 tape, 31 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1083 Alan Knox., 1 tape, 31 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1084 Burton Kreitlow., 1 tape, 31 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 1085 Alex Charters., 1 tape, 30 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 3/4 in. (Box 19)
  - Junto 2000 (Georgia Center for Continuing Education)
    - 1993 Mar 11, 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - 1993, Jun 17, 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - 1993, Sep 16, 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - 1993, Dec 16, "Show #4", 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - 1994, Mar 17, "Program #5", 3 tapes VHS (Box 21)
    - 1994, Jun 16, "program 6", 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - 1994, Sep 15, 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - 1994, Dec 15, 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - 1995, Mar [no day], 2 tapes VHS (Box 21)
    - 1995, Jun [no day], 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - 1995, Sep 21, 1 tape VHS (Box 21)
    - Undated, 2 tapes VHS (Box 21)
    - VC 7002 Junto 2000: March edition, 1 tape, 120 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 1/2 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 7003 Alex Charters interview, June 7, 1993; 1 tape U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 1/2 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 7004 Junto 2000, 1 tape, 120 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 1/2 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 7005 Junto 2000, 1 tape, 120 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 1/2 in. (Box 19)
    - VC 10556 Junto 2000: interviews with leaders in continuing education attending the 78th annual National University Continuing Education Association meeting in Nashville, TN, 1993; 1 tape, 117 min. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 1/2 in. (Box 19)
  - Conversations on Lifelong Learning
    - VC 7529 Conversations on Lifelong Learning (Gretchen Bersch, University of Alaska), 1995; A series of in-depth conversations with leaders in the field of adult learning. In each program a different educator shares thoughts about his/her early professional life, philosophies and theories, life's work and views of the future. Interviewees include Stephen Brookfield, Phyllis M. Cunningham, Cyril O. Houle, Malcolm Knowles, Alan Knox, Sharon Merriam, Jack Mezirow.; 7 tapes. U-Matic videocassette. Sound, color, 1/2 in. (Box 19)